

Chilean, Residence in Adelaide, Australia

🛮 484190364 | 💌 juliancabezas@gmail.com | 🌴 juliancabezas.com | 🖸 juliancabezas | 🛅 juliancabezas

Data science, Education, R, Python and Java Programming

Professional Profile

My way of working is based on the capability to face complex challanges regarding analyzing data from several sources, generating algorithms to analize social, economic and environmental data, with a focus on spatially explicit information. I work as consultant, full-time professional or researcher. As part of my job, I have generated multiple scientific publications and working papers, with the intention of sharing methodologies and approaches. I am also interested in education, participating in workshops and as assistant in several courses, while at the same time I am contantly involved in environmental education and musical projects.

Education

University of Chile Santiago, Chile

RENEWABLE NATURAL RESOURCES ENGINEER - BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN RENEWABLE NATURAL RESOURCES

2010-2015

2020-2021

University of Adelaide

Adelaide, Australia

MASTER OF DATA SCIENCE (CURRENT STUDENT)

Professional skills

- Development and implementation of spatial and statistic data analysis algorithms. Including machine learning algorthms.
- Advanced R programming skills.
- Basic Java, Python, SQL and Git skills.
- UAV Driving and data processing.
- Chilean driver licence (Class B). Valid for driving in Australia

LANGUAGES:

- · Native Language: Spanish
- Advanced level of English (score 7.5/9 in academic IELTS).
- Basic level of German (A1, certified at KIT, Germany).

Professional Experience

The Mullion Group Canberra, Australia

CASUAL CONSULTANT 2020 - Present

· Developing of a proof of concept of the implementation of the Generic Carbon Budget Model (GCBM) for forest carbon modelling

Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)

Santiago, Chile

NATIONAL PROJECT PERSONNEL FOR THE UNIT OF CLIMATE CHANGE AND ENVIRONMENTAL SERVICES, NATIONAL FORESTRY CORPORATION (CONAF)

· Support for the development of the digital platform of the Monitoring and Measurement System of the National Strategy of Climate Change and Vegetation Resources.

R&D Department - National Institute of Statistics

Santiago, Chile

STATISTICAL ANALYST

REMOTE SENSING SCIENTIST

2018 - 2019

2016 - 2017

· Development of statistic analysis algorithms, including text mining algorithms for automatic classification of labor sector in national surveys

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT)

Karlsruhe, Germany

Implementation of disturbance detection algorithms using latge scale satellite data (SaMovar Project)

University of Chile Santiago, Chile

GIS ASSISTANT 2015

• GIS elaborations and spatial analysis in the Study for the definition of protection areas in the east piedmont of Santiago project, financed by the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)

Consultancy_

- 2017: Report elaboration and participation as expert witness in the case D-33-2017 of the environment court of Santiago. with the report "Spatio-temporal analysis of causality and spatial extent of the Nilahue Barahona fire in January 2017".
- 2017: Report for the Forest Institute of Chile (INFOR): "Delineation and classification of water courses in forest basins in southern Chile: Analysis using remote sensing techniques" (forest and water research line)
- 2014: GIS advisor: Diagnosis of the agricultural and soil system of the area of influence of the Carén reservoir. Ambiente Seguro-CODELCO El Teniente. Mapping and analysis of land uses.

Academic achievements

- A complete list of my academic and professional publications and scientific congresses is available at this link
- Assistant in the following undergraduate courses (University of Chile):
 - 2012-2014: Statistics II.
 - 2013-2014: Hidrology.
 - **2011**: Botany.
 - **2011**: Applied Botany.
- Scholarship of excellence granted for being the higher score at the admission test for the Carrer of Renewable Natural Resources Engineering

Extra-curricular activity

- 2013: Student Representant at the school council (School of Agricultural Sciences)
- 2012 Board of the Student Center of the Natural Resources Engineering (Extension manager)
- 2010-2015: Different roles at the "Ecomapu" organization, where several environmental education activities were organized

Hobbies

- Trumpet player at Salsa, Cumbia and folkloric bands: Sambaigo, SuperChango and Chocolate.
- Participation at trumpet teacher at the "La Castrina" workshops, Santiago, Chile.

References_

- Dr. Fabian Fassnacht. Post-Doc Position. Institut für Geographie und Geoökologie, (Karlsruher Institut für Technologie, KIT). e-mail: fabian.fassnacht@kit.edu
- Dr. Jorge Pérez Quezada, Associate Professor. Faculty of Agricultural Sciences (University of Chile). e-mail: jorgepq@uchile.cl